all right hello YouTube and Facebook
your little greetings yes I can do the
intro so this is a bit of a unique
session we are going over the prototype
for the project tracker which hopefully
part of this will also be involved with
coming up with a better name but this is
something that we've been sort of
talking off and on about and people have
you know asked about something similar
in one degree or another in the Facebook
group I would say probably three to five
times at least
so other any questions before we get
started and do screen sharing and is it
okay if I put the link to their website
on the screen um yeah sure that made
sense okay Pablo there's been in the
works how long have you been working on
it I'm like the actual prototype maybe
two weeks
I like until I mean I technically added
the objects longer than that but not it
was barely started then so effectively
yeah I'd say about two weeks it is built
on the neck platform which means it's
not it's not coated it's kind of you
know a drag-and-drop
what-you-see-is-what-you-get style
editor there's definitely going to be
some features that you know people might
ask for that we just can builder that I
don't know how to build so this is kind
of meant to be a proof of concept that's
meant to get us as close to this as
possible we're we're seeing some
benefits out of it and then ideally
enough till we actually get some users
using it so people understand what we're
trying to do and then we can move into
an actual like coded version Hey and
Betty's here about him this is a
prototype exactly this is a prototype
then here Henley did you want to
anything before we get started with the
piece preacher did you already give
updates are we even doing that today I
can't remember now it's just the the
neck yeah and then yeah the only thing
is if we have enough time after the neck
one there's a another prototype I was
hoping to show about
the patio video chat stuff so cool if we
have to we'll take super long okay
so I won't really be able to see the
screen well on screen cherry because I'm
just on a single screen laptop so you
know feel free to shout or anything if I
see something important or so much
coolster being able to click on this
link that's in the thing can you put an
image you won't need to because I'll be
screen sharing and I can actually here
on site with me share my screen and then
we can switch the way that this is
arranged that I should have to do some
sharing of a nun sharing and then re
sharing just because all in my
Chromebook and don't have a ton of this
so let me switch oh really did that
perfect so we're looking at the public
for version versa mint and incognito tab
because I'm actually logged in in Chrome
so this is how it'll look if you just go
and view the the prototype without
looking in its gonna start you off on
the home page which has got a really
rough description of the different pages
available the home page in theory should
end up having sort of the most used
features things that will relate to the
other pages and you've got your two tabs
up here projects and events with sort of
some sub pages each under projects
project directory this is a list of all
the projects that have been submitted
and these are only ones that are being
marked as public
so there's actually more in the back end
I think like I want to say about two
months ago now we did an ask of the game
B projects community to say hey you know
can you go to this forum and enter in
your project so that we you know as
we're building something like this we
have Alessa projects to work from so I
made the ones public that either are
projects of people who are actually you
know involved in together tech or organ
V projects or have done us a project
raising so there are more in the backend
they just aren't pop-up public yet with
each one I'll use wiki election because
that's the one with the most sort of
information available you can view more
information about the project and again
this is made so you don't have to log in
to see this anybody can just go and view
you know what projects are public what
they're up to that kind of thing so
we're looking at the page for wiki
election you can see the basic
information like the project name what
category that's been put into the short
intro which is kind of just meant to be
a single you know sentence so you know
probably 10 words or less describing
what it does and then if you've got a
longer version you can put that in the
description and then of course links to
the various channels with all this it's
really easy to add field so if there's
like for example if we end up with a
bunch of projects that have patreon so
we can add an option the airport patreon
and the people can store their links so
there's active project members where
this is you know currently I'm the only
one there it says I'm the the product
owner
it says I'm the only sort of member
who's a part of it you can view more
there this is a very simple page again
we can add more there if needed the help
needed section is one of the I think
more useful areas so this is meant to be
you know if you go to a the illicit
projects and you view a project that
sounds interesting that project can then
say hey I need help in these areas and
so here you know were collection is
saying that we need help with sort of
communications in the social media area
there's probably a bunch more that I
should be adding but this is just as an
example and then there's again more
information about this health needed
post where it's saying hey we would be
if we can even help posting content
regularly on multiple channels to help
build an audience and as with everything
else we can you know tweak this to make
sure that like if Bentley wants to help
her ask for help with reason score and
there's something missing that here that
he would need to add in order to ask for
help that's a part of what we're looking
for feedback on is to make sure that
project owners feel that there's enough
here that they can actually use it to
indicate the areas that they need help
and then underneath we have the two
different event areas there's upcoming
events so you can see here there's the
wiki election livestream for tomorrow
it's got the public URL so again if you
had you know things scheduled in the
future this could be a spot where you
can just go to that page
you'll see later this is also listed
somewhere else so it just makes it easy
to see what all the different projects
have scheduled and be able to join from
here we are also tracking on the backend
what the I guess the panelist URL is so
if people sign up for events actually
you know join of the panelists where
they're you know using their webcam and
a microphone they'll have that URL
available if they've been registered and
then finally we have the completed
events which mostly make sense for
things like live streams because the
public URL turns into this you know
streaming later URL so if this was a
topic you're interested in you can go to
view it there those last two aren't
terribly important on the project page
but they're still there so you can see
it it's more useful when you're just
seeing a list of all the events so you
can see sort of what's coming up and
what's happened in the past and again
same kinds of information available the
other area under projects is for help
needed and so this is just a list of all
the different help needed posts that the
different projects have made so right
now there's only one from with the
election if we went to let's say a
reason score and Bentley had added
something under help needed then under
the Pelt needed page you would actually
see two posts one from wiki election the
one from reason score where of course
the Eagle here is to say hey here's you
know the five or ten areas that some
people across all these different
projects are looking for help and as it
gets into you know a lot more we can
start to add filters and give people the
ability to say hey show me you know
either what kind of like sense-making
projects need help or you can do
something like show me who needs help
with marketing because that's what I'm
good at that kind of thing and then it's
going to look the same as if you were to
view upon the project page it's just a
different way to see a list sort of
across all the projects does this make
sense so far yeah it looks good
so the second part to the public view is
the events so there's scheduled events
where these are things that are actually
you know in theory definitely going to
happen it's split into two sections one
is project event
so just like it sounds these are events
that are linked to a project same as
before you know if reason score had a a
live stream or an event published you
would see all the events across all the
different projects that are scheduled in
the future there's some amount of sort
of timezone translation here so we can
see you know that it's happening at noon
Pacific 3 p.m. Eastern 8 p.m. GMT or UTC
or whatever we want to call it and it
expected to be around an hour and again
delete join and then the other part are
the events that aren't linked to a
project so that's going to be you know
things like possibly idea cafes or just
something where you're trying to get
buy-in from multiple people to say yep I
would show up to that you know as a
finalist so it's not just one person
talking it's kind of trying to get um
the buy-in from people but these are
topics that are confirmed as yep you
know we got the minimum number of people
this should be happening and then under
events you've got proposed events which
these are meant to be events that people
are saying you know hey I'm interested
in talking about this here's the time
I'm interested in talking at the
duration and time zone stuff again and
then again you can see how many people
are confirmed so when you're signed in
as a member you'll be able to say you
know I want to go to that and then after
we get a certain number it can
automatically propose to the schedule
list so does that make sense for the
public view yeah perfect so now let me I
should go back here and stop sharing for
a second
yeah I'd gone in and put there was
already I think you had a stub in there
for reasons go I went and filled out a
few of the things I didn't get to the
events or the requesting people I might
go ahead and do that but it seems usable
and then if we want to go forward we
might just figure out how we want to
post about it because a couple people
keep kind of asking for this right sort
of thing when they come in but maybe we
should hear what Ghibli and Susan I
think and there is still the the member
area but if it is adding to no on the
public sort of before we switch hats you
get that and go to the back end yeah
yeah I don't think did I get an email
invite I think I do still need to like
do some testing and figure out how the
emails go out after you're approved you
have been you have been approved I
didn't add like the stub article for you
because I wasn't sure exactly how you
wanted to sort of spell or arrange the
Touro flow coming there wasn't sure
oh oh oh you ready bro and then flow all
together okay
cultural cultural content culture
comments okay yeah I had mostly right
okay he's checking again to see if there
was a way I could I can't put in events
I was under the events page or under
solution raising events what is the
option to add it that's what we're going
to go over next so the the member area
isn't ideal it's kind of a part of the
restriction in knack there's multiple
ways you can do it this seem to be that
the better way so we'll go through it
and if it's you know completely
offensive then we can look at some other
ways of doing it so now we're looking at
if you're logged in and it looks very
much the same you know you've got home
projects events that that's all exactly
the same the only thing different is you
have a new tab called member area if you
click on member area well I see that
image isn't loading anymore that's fun
it's just a screenshot saying to use
this section here so the idea is that
when you log in you go to member area
and now all of the things that sort of
you can do as a member
in this gray bar here so you know so you
can go to your account settings and do
your basic you know changing your email
and password and stuff like that you can
go to your my projects or so I've only
got the one project you can hit view and
sort of see how it looks or if you
actually want to change something you
can go there head--it and then you know
you can do things like saying actually I
don't want to publish it or but by
default like if you submitted your
project in the past when you sign up for
a member account and I notice it's you
I'll actually assign that to you so you
might already have one when you pop in
it'll default to not being published you
can say yes and then it will show up
when somebody who's you know a member of
the public and hasn't logged in they'll
be able to go to the project directory
and see your project if it's set to
published and then everything else is
just the details that we saw on that
page we probably do need to do some work
categories I think since making an
education or the only two I have it in
there right now we can add those quite
easily but for the ones that had in the
prototype those need to be the most
common culture honestly don't know what
sense and what um solution raising is
like solutions yeah I have a couple
different like groups of categories
where we'll have to figure it out to you
know have it makes sense it's more
important that sort of it works for
project owners you know that you feel
like yeah that um that generally sort of
somewhat decently categorizes the
project and it also makes sense for the
potential you know volunteers to show up
and it makes sense that that's how they
would structured the you know projects
that they might be interested in helping
out with yeah so you need to talk to
people and do card sorting right exactly
what is the dominant words that to do
that I need to get people involved
yeah so that's hopefully what this will
come up with and I would love your help
on that because it sounds like you're a
hell of a lot more experienced what
brand it comes to that kind of thing I
have I have some experience just not for
the last you know five or ten years okay
yeah so this is built so you could be
the owner of multiple projects and then
you know you can go in and view each one
you want to add a project there's just
the add project button and then you've
got your basic stuff here and then after
it's added you'll be the one that owns
it right now it's just one user per
project your your your essentially the
owner of that project record in the
database so you'll be the one who can
see it and you control if it's published
or not and then from here from view you
know you can do things like add project
roles where product accruals are made to
either say who is working on it or you
can say like yep they're active and
they're actually doing it you can pick
the member and so on or you can say we
need help and then it shows up in the
help needed section so it's kind of
meant for both not the most usable but
it's what we have for now under project
roles that's the actual roles that you
have in a project so of course in this
case I have a role as a product owner
wiki election if I were helping out on
reason score or something I might also
have a project role here for reason
score I wouldn't have a reason score
under my projects because I don't own it
but I can at least go there and change
like the information available in things
I don't own the project but I control
you know like for example if I wasn't
working on a project anymore I might be
able to deactivate my project role but
for now that's mostly on the project
owner side but would you have a spot
that we are able to you know give people
access to change their their their
project roles if they feel so inclined
if you were going to be volunteering on
projects and you didn't have a project
of your own in mind projects page would
be empty and then your project roles
page will have every role that you play
across possibly multiple projects right
so if you were volunteering with three
projects you have three project roles
and no projects does that make sense
mmm-hmm
and then finally we have B my events and
there is the my events with those again
are the events that you own so it's
similar to two to the projects where one
user can sort of add an event and keep
it up to two to date with things as they
change you can see I have two ones in
the past ones in the future and then if
you sign up for an event and you have a
role and it's sort of you know you
aren't the owner but you want to be able
to for example say actually no I'm not
coming or if there's some amount of back
and forth and being able to control how
and when and if you're you know
interacting with an event that you don't
home that's done under event invitations
so event invitations the ones that I've
said yes I'm watching
yes I'm participating in yes everybody
participating and all running it
technically it would show up here and
then if you're watching it you don't
need to register you can just go to the
scheduled events and click there to
watch it and it's more we you know if
future people want to be able to sort of
like bookmark things that you know if we
end up with a bunch of events and people
want to be able to say well that sounds
interesting you know I want to see that
and sort of a separate list of things
that I've curated for myself we can
build that but then under events also
there's the ability to add events there
so for the times for right now
everything is entered in Pacific time
and then the other fields are are
calculated right so it just says the
eastern time is just the Pacific time
plus three hours and GMT is the Pacific
time plus eight hours and then if you
know there's some need to have the end
time we can also calculate you know take
the start time add the duration to it
and that's your year end time I figured
that having start time and duration is
probably enough for now but we can tweak
that as needed
yeah I'm not sure if you'll be able to
keep up with the changing the
differences between GMT and you might
just take that out and make people
we might be able to do an automated link
to one of the time and date websites
that will give them lots of it yeah and
yeah if this ends up being unwieldy then
yeah we can totally do it
each one is a separate ones like if
we're saying you know that GMT just
changes at a different time it can be a
pain but it's just going in and changing
one field on the back end say oh now
it's you know it's plus seven instead of
plus eight and then a week later
changing it back yeah well but only B
you would change it like when the winner
America does it you probably change PT
or PPD you wouldn't but you would change
eastern time and actually wouldn't
because they would yes I think the only
thing that would be weird
it is GMT because they change their
clocks at a difference a couple weeks
different yeah well I agree yeah it's a
bit messy in it yeah I guess it's a
better way to do it you'll have a
problem because of the dates in the
future then some will be in the future
during the change them well that's why
it might be good just to take it off for
now cuz it all it won't be right
perfectly I think they've all now
changed over and we have until fall and
who knows what the world looks like in
fall right yeah if there's Australia and
North America all change their clocks
were good until the fall and that is a
decade away very true yeah and this is
just meant to be sort of you know again
part of the prototype I find that most
people are pretty good at knowing how to
convert their own time zone you know so
people get used to like oh hey it's a
new Pacific that's of a Pacific is a
fairly standard one so hopefully people
will know how to convert it um but if we
can sort of make this work more group
more gracefully then I think it's
helpful to be able to just you know go
onto the column and say okay that's it
get my time cool especially if you have
people from various time zones although
I guess they all have them is it for
time anyway so that's kind of moved but
I think that's about it to show for the
prototype so far so you have your public
version with projects and events and
then your your your member account you
go to member area it's the gray bar up
here and you can change your own account
project that Rosie playing a project and
your events during this time period
solution raising is to have somebody add
a project or do that during this time
that maybe we could do that on a
different video and upload it just so
people know how they can add their
projects to to it themselves I did it
and it was fairly intuitive and if I can
do it even though I hate slack and I
hate discard and I hate certain other
things it's fairly user friendly so yeah
and I fully understand the you know
people have some reluctance to sign up
for yet another member account
I'm 100% I understand all of that but at
this point that's a there is the ability
to have some sort of single sign-on but
it seems to be like for companies so
it's got like Facebook and Google how
it's made if like you're all a part of
the same domain which we aren't at the
moment then that won't work so for now
you do have to have a a member account
from the right up on the nak website
they're supposed to be fairly secure
they have like a pretty detailed page on
their security methodologies so we'll
see how it it works up the back time
[Music]
good work thank you if you guys have any
questions about that either in a session
or anyone watching feel free to reach
out and as I think I've sort of hinted
at the beginning I think Susan had
signed up for an account I have to go in
there to prove it right now I don't
think efforts approved I don't think it
sends them an email so like now I think
Susan was notified but now you can go in
there and use your account and you'll be
able to sign in add projects of whatnot
so that's a part of what I'll have to do
at some point is actually going to add
the alerts for when they're set to
active right and that and therefore
generates an email exact because it does
generate an email to me to let me know
that somebody
registered it's just when I go in there
and set them as active there's no email
back to you saying hey that user account
you asked for it it's active now yeah
that's really important because I find
in a lot of the UX stuff that I've done
that there is this initial yes I want to
do it and then if there is a delay even
of sometimes hours especially if it's a
day people just don't even respond yeah
which I might if it's easy to change I
might just take off the need for
activation until it becomes a problem
like it's really only manda you know
there's people in there that for some
reason we don't want in there people are
standing it then I can go in there and
turn it on but that's actually probably
a better thing to do so now we can
invite people in the game be projects
group to come and add their own and they
have to go through the same process
Susan did write of requesting it and
then yeah and if they don't have our
project if they don't have a project
they can still sign up there's sort of
two different views for like if you have
a project versus if you don't i've got
away on the back end to note who's a
project owner it's mostly the same i
think it just did it won't show you
projects but like you still you can
still have events you can still have
project roles you can still manage your
member account one of the ways that
still needs improvement of the things
that still needs improvement is if
you're a member like going to an event
being able to sort of sign up for an
event easily and see if you're signed up
but everything else there's there
there's ways to go at it and you can see
your event roles and add them now it's
just not the most intuitive it would be
better to have a list of events you can
go to the event and see here's who
signed up
oh I'm signed up that kind of thing I
mean you have several people using this
and we do have like like anything right
if it's only the three of us there's no
point but if there are on four of us I
guess using it only the four of us it
won't be much point but if we have
multiple people using it put in an event
so we can see what events are going on
and find out what common events we want
to have it can be a very very useful
tool so thank you for making it
betta see if it doesn't back to get some
yeah I mean clearly where you're
building for the future so right
building so that also making sure that
people who don't have projects but are
interested in helping out that's a clear
distinction otherwise right and that's
why there's like a fair amount to the
the public portions people who just
wanted to kick tires they did they can
show up see projects see who needs help
see the events well you can even just
use that to manage the event it's like
to just go there to see what's going on
oh it sounds cool click to view that
kind of thing
the thing right there the only other
fields that you might add to the actual
project information itself would be
perhaps something about when it started
like and sort of a timeline some sort of
indication of where you are with respect
to what you're doing and yeah I can have
that that might be useful yeah I guess I
mean it'll be optional so we can you
know stick it on there you can fill it
out if you want to if not you know it
can be on there and empty No
yeah the world so if we like it maybe we
should go ahead and kind of figure out
we're on Facebook we want to in the
group to kind of make it visible sure I
I would say before we make it visible
I'd want there to be more projects than
just wiki election Google Voice
information so like yeah if you want to
go in there and add an event and or you
know a help needed just so that if
somebody is poking around like once when
we launch it then they can see like okay
there's two or three projects and you're
asking for help but having events and
like cool you can see the the early days
of what it's going to look like if we
get you know 10 or 20 or 50 active
projects yeah I can definitely add to
needed people and maybe jublee can get
in and put our regular recurring events
or yeah yeah yeah great and then again
if there's any fields or like if there's
a value in a field that you need please
just you you can reach out directly on
Facebook and I can go in there and add
it pretty quickly so I'm just trying to
though picture on where on the Facebook
right post it so we could add it to the
to the pinned
post although we might need to clean
that up a bit to make room I don't know
if there's any other place I think a pin
post makes sense I'm wondering if once
we get sort of some decent sample data
possibly even just from us if we when
you want to do like a single you know a
one-time cross post like in the game
view homepage or like you know ask Jim
if we can be like hey because now that
kind of starts to bridge the gap of if
you don't have a project but you want to
help with the project yeah
now that community idea and I think they
said periodic updates from the
individual groups is actually desired so
I think like yeah good it is the bigger
meta project update is it is very yes
game be main group right okay yeah
that's really important too because when
I first came in I just went to the main
game B page and hung out there for a
while but then I want to do something I
want to build something so then I found
your page right yeah
and one of the things I hinted at in the
beginning definitely open to better
names than project tracker because
that's I mean it's kind of descriptive
but also kind of vague because I know
that one of the posts was sort of taught
was more thinking I liked I think the
person who posted thought that it was
meant to track kind of like the game B
project is in like the separate pages
and they're like why wouldn't I just use
the game B homepage I was like okay it's
not those it's these and then banner
said Africa was explained but yeah yeah
I can't think about it clarify that
definitely think of each Facebook page
as a project but really those are
community could be like they could be in
there but also they don't have like
that's not the point
and they're not the only ones so I know
so we posted on online tools which is
specifically true it's great so maybe
something like emerging game B projects
yeah we once it gets my sure enough we
might want to ask me wiki of about like
updating the projects page to point
there you like oh if you want this
you should be here go here instead
because that's the new home for it yeah
yeah the wiki did it ever come back up
oh yeah is it down I've been down ages
okay so that that might be moved itself
I think fell a part of it as projects
and one of the things that I think will
end up being an issue slash question is
just like which projects how do we
explain if you have a project is it
applicable to join this group or is it
like to game a I think most people here
err on the side of just join and we'll
see if there's like oh you know you're
trying to to buy and sell slaves okay no
not you you don't get to join most most
group I'm trying to think of a good
gaming example that one's perfect in a -
marketplace for slave for human slaves
and I mean there's gonna be some that
yeah like you're low even if you're you
haven't like a local food grocery store
how'd it like it has to be pretty game
be for not to be different in there see
if it's local like is it although maybe
not I don't know one of the like game
any kind of pillars like you know if
it's on the win if it's Andy rival risks
like it actually so you can create some
sort of an information that goes with it
right and sort of a checklist do you
feel that you fall into this category
these categories which sort of broadly
describe it what a game B project is if
so you know make sure you join up but if
not maybe you could give it and I
probably err on the side of like making
a list that's kind of meant to be a hey
here are some examples and not going too
hard on those if you're if you're this
kind of project go away we don't want
you of course was that here's what we do
want and then if we have people join up
who have you know the Craigslist for for
slaves were like okay we probably should
have said no slavery coops are bad and I
do think that yeah a little bit we go
with it until we get someone who is
then we're like wait what was it about
this one that wasn't that was so game a
or so not that that's sometimes easier
rather than thinking of everything you
could possibly be like I just said about
the food co-op right yeah well there is
one that's absolutely suitable then if
you think that yours is a
command-and-control sort of game we're
not really interesting yeah yeah right
do we run we're going to yours Bentley
are we done with first time i
screenshare done so this this one
alright I think we have to add it to the
permission
speaking of command and control no you
know yeah so this is actually not the
one I wanted to show but who was working
on this site this is one of the options
so this is Jonas or yonis his site that
he created to kind of help us kind of
have discussions so you would go in here
and type in your name and then it shows
up like these are rooms where things can
be happening or you could start a new
one which I haven't tried which is
actually he's got a really nice design
here so let's join the ALU in Jo GI
these are all tests oh yeah so yeah so I
think he's still kind of working on this
apparently I just have the oh no
something's popping up I haven't played
with this it's probably a video and it's
not working because I'm already using my
camera and what is this built-in that
does not know actually no it's not it's
not knack he's using a react as the as
the framework
yeah stuff like that hard coded this is
not a drag-and-drop thing right yeah
this is he's a he's doing development
straight local development so that was
kind of an idea to have a rooms where he
could then join and later we were gonna
try and limit the number of possible
participants and I guess you could have
topics based on the room name and yeah
so you can delete rooms anyway so that's
where he is on that one which is kind of
starting jubblies initial concept and
correct me if i'm wrong was that oh well
no we talked about several different
things one of them was kind of a
scheduling systems where you could put
in your available time and and it would
let you know when a group of like three
or four people had overlapping available
hours was one of the options we
discussed that's not one of the options
that I have but the other option which
fits all so what shoot I forgotten his
name now yeah saying that that you would
have a place where you can see all the
different rooms see who's in them and
then participate which is very similar
to what what Jonas was working on this
is one this is called keiko chat and it
actually has a lot of features it's a
fully fledged community space especially
built for moderators community
moderators and stuff but this one is
their prototype called the gardens and
actually have one that I created called
the patio because that's what Nick was
calling it but you can see that you can
join the video the main room you're in
or you can go down and look these other
rooms right now there's three people in
the central garden where we are and then
you can you can go into any of the other
rooms and change the topics to say what
you want to talk about so far if I enter
this I should have entered one I could
actually read the name of
yeah and Kiko Chavez ki kale cute all
right
vhat dot-com and there's a lot of
features in here like you can see
there's a live chat over here for this
whole circle which would be for all the
all the rooms and the the whole kind of
community and then you can you can go
into any group and then you can hit this
join the video and then you would be
kind of in the video room they also have
like dot you know collaborative editing
documents and event schedules and lots
of different stuff that we go over but
this just seemed to fit exactly what
Nick was talking about it's where you
could see what what people are in what
rooms and join them and see what they're
talking about it doesn't have a like a
preview of the actual video screen which
is one is there a limit to the number of
people that can be in the video room
they use a zoom in the backend so oh wow
now so the pricing model for this is if
you build it there's quite a few pricing
models like he has one where well I put
this way you can you can actually charge
people to join it's built in three month
increments you can set it to whatever
amount you want
he then charges that central like owner
of the site a number of cents per minute
of video per person which is he actually
just bills you for the zoom costs so
he's not making any profit off this so
that's what zoom charges in the back of
your if you're using the system so if
you charge everyone three dollars a
month or it be nine dollars for three
months as the minimum billing cycle then
you each person could do about 10 hours
of video before you start going into the
REC I was thinking if we wanted to we
talked about 10 hours over sorry three
months or one over a months okay well 10
hours per month or 30 hours and three
months yeah okay is what it comes out to
and then of course you could you could
increase the costs if if on average
everyone's doing that much
so you can also charge whatever amount
you want in a three-month cycle so I was
thinking that we could do $15 for three
months and have the extra money go
towards funding
together tech projects now we do have
some of the kind of fiscal problems with
that is that it'll be tied to someone's
account the one I created of course tied
to my account has my credit card on it
so if someone sits on video for three
months then I would be built for that
also yeah also if any extra funds come
out they would that would go to my
account too so we'd have to do something
to kind of like manage you know we had
four people paying $15 a month and this
is a charge and what are we doing with
extra money how do we make sure that I
don't just go to Cancun on it oh that's
a good idea
I think I did game beat yeah game bi
coach at comm we could change it to get
together techie coach at comm so this is
just I was usually the other one is the
demo because it there was more people in
there but right now it's just me cuz no
one has this and you have to create an
ID and you'd have to actually pay to get
in and then yeah I mean we could make it
free but then I would my credit card to
be billed for all the video hours but
all the community tools are pretty much
free and it's a lot more you can do than
this video chat I just want to kind of
show that feature cuz that's what people
were talking about and then we can look
at the other tools and see if there's
more that we wanted to do anyway so
that's an option it kind of fits several
more ideas
what is the security level on this I I
mean I know the developer and choosing
zoom is the backend so owned by Google
now is that true that's what I heard I
have not
that you don't know I know they've been
getting in a lot of security related
trouble recently but yeah ya know most
of their security related trouble was
because they overstated their security
stance it's and then you know people
were kind of getting in and because
they're you know people are able to get
into your video and stuff like that but
it's not like we're talking about
health-related we don't the we shouldn't
be doing anything in here I mean you
don't want it to be public like you
don't want people taking videos of you
talking and private and going out but
there shouldn't be an API a PII our pH I
in this platform at all right sometimes
I think they were also sending even if
you didn't have a Facebook account they
were sending information about the like
the meetings and stuff I guess that they
learned to Facebook now you guys stop
that but they're they gotten some pretty
hot water yeah correct the tool you
showed near the beginning with it yonas
it made mm-hmm how much did you know the
price point on that one weather no
Aussie onus and whether it like if we
are using it how much it cost the person
and then how much we would pay for that
because that is like one cent per minute
per person doesn't seem like a like I
know when I was using stream yard I was
just setting up conversations with
people in game it was hard to stay under
20 hours a month and that was only two
of us right not like if you have ten
people and four people are watching and
six people are having a conversation the
four people still count and it's it can
get rather astronomically expensive
especially um anyway yes like $15 for
three months seems like a doable I would
sign up for that but I know that'll be a
sticking point for a lot of people and
I'm if there is a way for us to start
for free or for cheap or for by donation
where you don't I mean if this costs him
a hundred bucks a month that actually
seems better than one cents a minute
cuz it's like you know like per person
for like I'm just wondering I don't
think his the video on his solution is
gonna have any different pricing models
and between the two solutions for the
yeah yeah that's going into the back
ends it is I'm sorry so it's a zoom API
that people are plugging in I don't
that's what that's what's it the other
one I don't know what yonus to chose
here and I you know I could probably try
and figure it out but again yeah I can I
can ask him ask him if he knows the
price point I'm so I wasn't aware that
this particular one was also zoom I
thought it was just a text chat so it's
I think that was his intent I don't know
how far he got and I don't know I don't
actually see any controls coming up so
maybe he hasn't even put that in the
thing to see if I can look in so I I
don't know how far he's gotten I just
know he had like owner first talking it
wasn't even important to have a oh it
was just helping people get together and
then they would have to figure out their
video issues so you know they'd be
limited to 45 minutes well it has a lot
of notes coming back in here we are able
to use zooms free option and just key
because you can use the URL we use it
for a mega group all the time we just
click on the same one constant we just
go out and come back in that it's up to
like the group whether they want to pay
for a user account or not rather than at
all because if you're going with zoom
embedded in your technology then it's
always 1 cent per minute per user and
you can't really get the free option or
the like group option right where you
pay 20 bucks a month for unlimited or
whereas if we like if there is a way to
embed that in this then we get the best
of both worlds but I don't know what
Jonas has done or whether that's
possible or any of it so I will I'll ask
you a nice the pricing on it because
that's just yeah now the with the
benefit of going with this other thing
is that is that we were talking about
having a way to have people contribute
monthly to this and I don't think
there's any way in the world that video
costs would go above
unless we have a bad actor like we said
and then we kick that person out but I
don't think there's a chance that the
video costs would go above and we could
make it ever one you know it could be
nine dollars for three months it could
be fifteen dollars for three months it
could be anything but then we do have
we've already kind of started our next
step in the process of having people
choose to donate money on a regular
basis to get two together texts so we
can start doing something with it now I
don't know if we're ready for it but
they have a funding model that you can
do that with that these other systems
well I don't know
so yella stood then have to set up a
whole billing system what the whole
thing that's the thing with Kiko
chapters the Billings kind of built in
now it's not as flexible as I wanted to
be nice if we could send people and give
them a free month
yeah the trial which I can I can talk to
them and see if we can get that type of
stuff put it I have a plague yeah I know
nak also has some built in some building
stuff and you can charge people and you
know credit card them way off I'm sorry
that and then if we wanted to do that
patreon beltzman option like four
together tech just to do like the
monthly donation days but then that
probably wouldn't be related to Kiko
chat that would just be to fund whatever
way and I'm doing with it whether it's
Kiko chat or custom development or what
yeah I think it's the issue with getting
the funds moved around to the right
place yeah exactly
and it's I not sure how the name
alignment works technically wiki
election is incorporated and has a bank
account so I mean if we're just wanting
to like keep it out of people's personal
accounts I mean then it's getting named
wikis account and then it's yeah there's
still like the tracking part which I'm
definitely not signing up for cuz I'm
not a big fan of accounting and all that
jazz but just saying like if the you
know we're trying to keep it out of
people's personal accounts for text
stuff like that that's why I set up with
you and I think the point where we have
multiplied right now stream yard works
for us to have our conversations right
because there's under six of us yeah
once we you can even go on to zoom and
have it
more about the coordination and doing
those things I like I really like yonis
is one I also really like keepo chat but
it's Jonas this one is even more it
feels to be more intuitive more it's
like oh it's just a list of rooms I can
join rather than the other one looks I
don't know it was felt less like yes
it's not trying to be a full ecosystem
it's just really Purpose Driven just one
thing jet c.org which they say is a
completely free video conferencing so he
may have found an option that I mean
free sounds good and then like was well
funny tell you until we need money right
like I'm just saying
free is very bad free services is bad
game AAA not necessarily game P because
they're not giving it to you out of well
rank like why is it freeze a question
saying the farm we're getting money from
people the only is like transparency on
why are we asking for money where is it
going and I don't think there's a
problem with this costs us nine dollars
every three months we're getting 15 to
six is going into here what we're doing
with that we don't know yet we'll know
in the future the other issue is little
logistics of we need a bank account or
together tech and there has to be
signers and we have to figure that out
and do do that portion of it which at
the moment probably makes sense that a
jury just because Pedro and I are both
in this like we need to people that are
signers in the same logistical location
so but even then we're actually not that
question if we can get three we can
incorporate as a society and then
there's no tax third BC person like
that's the point is like you can't have
people all over the states and canada
and australia and like all these things
aren't designed for another canadian
might be okay i think you have to be the
majority BBC but i think it actually
might be okay for them to be i yeah i
think i think i believe it's over half
has to be in DC for a busy society and
technically we could do a federal one
but that's just a bit harder on the
paperwork side but it's just like the
logistics of we need money to go into
account we need accounting and then the
actual transparency of here's a rat this
is why we're asking for money this works
and it needs easy the spreadsheet right
like yes we thought we would have this
much zoom time we've actually is this
much we're in the red that we're in the
green were it you know like showing that
this is the case instead of just being
transparent which to me is very how we
get to Game B is through that around
that time is probably what when we'll
start getting deeper into the what would
you need to trust an organization that
was you know doing the kind of things
that we say we're doing and standing for
what we say we stand for what does that
mean you know you trust us or don't
trust me a lot yeah one other options I
don't know how hard it could get to get
set up as if we could get into hope and
collective which is mostly for
open-source software but they they end
up being the fiduciary it's their bank
account and then as people do things you
submit an invoice and that invoice is
all tracked and it's all open source so
anyone can then look and see where the
funds are going anyone can submit an
invoice and then we would approve so
there's no tax issue so there's it's
fully open source I'd be great the
problem is usually you have to have an
open source software project although
they say they handle other stuff anyway
so if we're going to spend time looking
into it I would I would include that as
well because that sounds a lot easier if
we can get past their hurdle yeah no
that sounds like a good a very good
option I think we looked into it before
yeah seemed like the most viable option
although like this tool we looked at the
one Adriel did isn't open source right
like it also is like our intention is to
make one that is open source at some
point in time it's just not there yet
and we're using the tools of our ability
I don't know if they care about that
right I don't know if that's under there
Brock receivers no yeah yonis is one as
technically open source he it's already
on github and anyone can see it so we
could put that under a group name of
together tech and github and then apply
but normally you need over a hundred
people they used to have it they've
changed the website some a hundred
people start the project before they
even look at it but projects there is
always the option like and game B itself
but I think you
like I don't could I go and store it do
I have to be a coder or be someone who's
actually technically you just have to
create an account at github and store it
I think although if they look at that
that's a whole bunch of non developers
and I want to but I want to make sure
that we're we're doing it it's designed
for open source software but I think
they also had it for open source
software or nonprofits so even though
we're technically not eat either we fit
the goal of what they're trying to do
it's just whether they would believe us
or not yeah and I mean if we
incorporated as a society I think that's
arguable nonprofit and then were ours
probably good time to mention that I
will not be here tomorrow with the
Saturday morning conversation I did
snake the stream yard and posted in the
group but I have won't be here because I
have a conversation with somebody Jordan
put me in touch with at 10:00 he so I
was like ok I'm doing my thing at 8:30
that night it'll be way too much so with
someone who's on the Dow stack and his
project is a community app on the Dow
stack that they're they're creating and
it's called community and it's just to
be out in June and so I'm looking
forward to our conversation I will
clearly know more about that as of
tomorrow after cool waldron called for
tomorrow but Susan or either one get
interested in being that the second
talking head in the wiki election live
stream it's on politics so like
politicians elections political parties
sure what time is it again just it is
noon pacific so one your time okay yeah
I'll be there what do you mean by second
talking head do I have to prep this like
no so how it works it'll kind of be
similar to the two to the first part
we'll all I'll share my screen and sort
of go through the slide deck I've got
like kind of three three sections to it
where I cycle between the three
different topics and there was anything
like do you want I did with Edie Edie
molar on we started on like sort of
scientific
discussion but we ended up talking about
the whole thing like I showed you
different slides and talked about it and
that seemed to really help and it's kind
of interesting to play with like here's
the starting point of the conversation
that frames most of it but it's all
interrelated that's why it has these
three kind of very separate feature sets
they'll bleed into each other call
that's alright I might be able to make
it what time zone compared to this
because they did you say that's too
central yeah and I every other week so
the one that I had some somebody already
joined was the science one which is fine
if somebody wants to join that one again
I did one on news and no one was there
for that was about two weeks ago and
then tomorrow we'll do politics and then
I just cycled through those three topics
every two weeks so if it's not tomorrow
it could be a later one too but I can
make it tomorrow I'll be a second head
okay do you have a link for that or are
you gonna yeah I can send you after cuz
I'm in string here now so I don't want
to cause it I don't send Brad the link
for tomorrow because we've been talking
on Twitter so cool it's awesome and I
also under each our 10 because their
next solution racing this Wednesday live
at 8:30 is on packaging and so if you
have a interest okay nice I'll be
interested to watch that one later that
much I'm cool materials and I'll put the
event on the other other one what won't
put all of my live events in the morning
but the ones on Wednesday are specific
just amazing so say more closing
statements or should we say goodbye to
YouTube and Facebook I'm good we'll see
you